Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Fire! Fire!
Come quick! Fire! Fire!
Come quick!
Fire!
Who’s there? What’s going on over there?
This is the arsonist.
What happened?
His Majesty the Emperor!
Everything’s all right now. Don’t be scared.
Meizhuang, she -
Lady Vertu, how are your wounds?
She must be scared speechless.
It’s all my fault.
Why did I ask Meizhuang to come
play Go today?
Rest assured, Your Highness.
Lady Vertu’s spirits are fine.
However, her burn is a little severe.
Why was there a fire out of nowhere?
Where is the head eunuch?
I beg Your Majesty’s pardon.
It’s all due to my carelessness.
However, we’ve already caught the arsonist.
He is awaiting your judgment.
Did someone intentionally set this fire?
Yes.
Bring him.
Bring him!
This eunuch was found
sneaking around when the fire broke out.
I discovered flint and lighting oil on him.
We’ve seized both the perpetrator and the evidence.
Whose palace are you from?
Your Majesty, he served Companion Nian
in the Palace of Earthly Honor.
His name is Suxi.
I don’t know how I offended this eunuch, to make him
want to murder me and destroy my palace.
Fortunately, the servants noticed the fire quickly.
Otherwise, I might not have lived to see Your Majesty again.
Your Majesty, my father and Concubine Sourire’s father
both contributed to quelling the Nians.
I’ve heard that Companion Nian
has been at odds with Sourire.
Now that she has been demoted,
she must be resentful of Sourire and me.
If not, why would a mere eunuch
dare to set fire to the Palace of Pearl Jade!
There must be someone behind him.
Companion Nian's resentment
is only directed at me.
I would never expect her to harm Lady Délice and Meizhuang.
I didn’t want to kill her so she could
have an opportunity to redeem herself.
Who would have thought
she could become even more vicous.
Very well,
tell the Empress and Consort Estime
to interrogate Suxi overnight.
If he confirms the accusation, send Nian to
the Cold Palace and grant her suicide.
They don’t need to report back.
Yes.
Although my palace is smaller than the Palace of
Pearl Jade, you can stay here for the time being.
I’m very glad to stay here.
Do you remember, when we were young,
we used to talk to each other in bed like this?
Yes.
It’s almost [lunar] New Year.
Nian Shilan’s sentence shouldn't be
delayed until next year.
That would be inauspicious.
Today is the 25th, and the
latest day should be the 29th.
That will make my wounds worthwhile.
The Empress and Consort Estime are
long-term enemies of Nian Shilan.
If she ever fell in their hands, she would have
been found guilty even without evidence.
And now there’s ironclad evidence.
Why did you have to burn yourself?
Fortunately, it's in winter.
If it were summer, it would fester.
At worst, I will have a scar.
It’s a fair trade for Nian Shilan’s life.
Only when His Majesty saw me wounded
would he see how serious the fire was.
And he would realize how devastated he would have
been if you had been caught in the fire,
so he can hate Nian Shilan to the bone.
I wouldn’t have known I could be this cruel
if she didn’t force me to be.
When Nian Shilan is dead, I won’t even know
who to engage in a fight with.
Anyone can be your enemy in the palace.
But it's also easy to avoid rivalry -
fade into obscurity and subject yourself
to being slain by others.
There will be an unending stream of new concubines.
Don't think that your future days will be spent alone.
I’m worried about your burn.
Does it still hurt?
It’s fine.
When the wound heals,
I will bring you the Scar Relief Gel.
It is the best for treating scars.
Companion Nian is cruel and shows no remorse.
She commanded Suxi to set fire to
the Palace of Pearl Jade.
I have decided death will be her punishment
for such an unpardonable crime.
Otherwise, there will be no
order and justice in the harem.
Your Majesty disciplines the harem rightfully.
We respect and obey Your Majesty.
Nian has served His Majesty for many years.
I will show mercy by keeping her corpse whole.
Autumn, tell Mr. Su to prepare
poisoned wine, a knife, and a length of white silk.
She will be allowed to choose her own end,
in consideration of her service to His Majesty.
Your Majesty is merciful.
If it were me,
I would have decapitated her with one swing,
due to her lawless acts.
You may all sit.
Yes.
Concubine Aide,
what is the matter?
Your Majesty. I’ve been feeling exhausted recently and
haven’t improved even after taking many medicines.
I’m sorry for my manners.
Sit down quickly.
Yes.
You must be tired from taking care of Wenyi
and preparing for the New Year.
You must take good care of your health.
Your Majesty must be tired from
interrogating Suxi last night.
You should have some rest.
We should take our leave now.
All right, you may all leave.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
Jinxi.
When is Mr. Su going to escort Nian to her death?
Executions in the Cold Palace happen at sunset.
Help me do my hair well.
I’m going to bid farewell to Her Highness Consort Fleur.
You've got some mettle,
entering the Cold Palace like this.
I've come here before.
This is where I saw
Concubine Beauté acting deranged before me.
I won't be!
You set me up to be where I am today.
I won't let you go even after I die.
Nobody ever set you up.
You harvest what you plant.
It was you who ordered Lady Chun drowned.
It was you who had Princess Wenyi's
food laced with cassava starch.
You asked Yu to poison me.
You had Meizhuang pushed into the pond,
and made all believe she feigned a pregnancy for favor.
You were behind all these, weren't you?
I knew it!
That bitch Cao Qinmo dared betray me,
only because you were plotting in the shadows.
How would she have the guts otherwise?
You don't really know her.
You used Wenyi repeatedly to gain favors,
even putting her life at risk.
Concubine Aide is her birth mother;
she has every reason to hate you.
Do you really think she
developed her hatred only recently?
"The ice three feet deep isn't grown in one day."
You should've sensed her loss of faith long ago.
In the prime of my power,
even that crone, the Empress
had to show me respect.
Cao Qinmo was merely a dog following me around.
Why would I pay any attention to her?
But she is a human being -
humans are much more sophisticated than dogs.
Bitch!
You are just as cunning as your father.
Were it not for your father's cunning schemes,
the Nian family wouldn't have crumbled into ruins!
You joined forces from inside and outside the palace
and the sole purpose was to
put me to death, wasn't it?
The Nian family would have never come to this day
without numerous wrongdoings,
arrogance, and recklessness.
Don't you forget that your husband is the Emperor!
An emperor would never tolerate
sharing his bed with a traitor.
My brother is an official with great merits.
He pacified the Northwest for the Great Qing.
He accomplished extraordinary feats!
He is but a servant to His Majesty
regardless of his accomplishments!
How dare he place himself above the Emperor?
Wasn't that treason?
- Why are you here?
- I came with My Lady.
Concubine Sourire is in there?
By decree of the Empress,
I have to send Nian off now.
Do what you must -
My Lady is here to see her off.
Hurry in now, so your task won't be delayed.
Peace to Your Highness, Concubine Sourire.
Please rise, Mr. Su.
By decree of Her Majesty the Empress,
you can choose one for yourself, My Lady.
The decree of the Empress?
Where's the edict of His Majesty?
His Majesty gave full authority
to Her Majesty the Empress.
I will not die without His Majesty's edict.
His Majesty himself wrote the edict to kill my brother;
it won't be hard for him to do the same to me.
His Majesty has said that
he doesn't want to hear
anything relating to you, My Lady.
Does His Majesty really detest me so much?
Go request His Majesty's edict.
I'll wait here.
Mr. Su, please give us some time.
Allow me ...
to bid my farewells to Companion Nian.
Yes.
Take your time, Your Highness.
I'll be waiting outside.
My apologies.
I've grown accustomed to calling you Your Highness.
It feels so strange
to hear you addressed as Companion.
My hand warmer is getting cold.
Go add some charcoal.
Yes.
But My Lady, it's dangerous for you to be here alone.
Just go. If there's any disturbance,
Mr. Su and the others are right outside.
Yes.
Do you know
why His Majesty loathes you?
His Majesty has never loathed me.
His Majesty was always so fond of me.
Even if I made many mistakes,
no matter how angry he got,
he could not bear to ignore me for too long.
Do you know why His Majesty likes you?
Simply for your beauty?
The palace has never lacked for beautiful women.
Are you suggesting that His Majesty favored me
because I'm Nian Gengyao's sister?
Consort Honnête also comes from
the family of a distinguished general.
The truth is clear as glass to your heart,
so why keep deluding yourself?
Nonsense!
How can His Majesty not have true affections for me?
Maybe he did.
But you and Nian Gengyao
have been arrogantly domineering for years.
I doubt he has
even a shred of affection left.
What would a wretch like you know?
I remember when I married into the family,
I was entitled Lord Consort
and became his most favored woman.
There were many women in his estate.
Everyone was afraid of him, except me.
He often took me horse-riding and hunting.
He said he was fond only of me.
But how numerous were the women in his estate!
So numerous that it enraged me.
He would stay with a lord concubine one night
and with a lord consort the other.
I would wait and wait,
till the sky was lit.
He still didn't come to me.
Have you ever tasted the bitterness of
waiting for someone dusk to dawn?
He is the Emperor - I knew that from the start.
His nights
would never belong to just me.
Of course.
You've never loved His Majesty as I have.
Later on, when I was pregnant,
His Majesty was overjoyed.
But over time,
his joy faded.
Even though His Majesty didn't say so,
I could feel it.
The Third Prince was the only son
growing up in the estate.
I knew that he was worried.
So I told him,
"No need to worry."
"I will give birth to a prince for you."
Yet, not long after that,
I took the prenatal tonic
that Consort Honnête served me
and lost my child!
The imperial doctor told me
my child had taken shape of a baby boy!
You lost your child,
so you wanted bury my child alongside yours?
He was only four months in my belly.
And you planned to put him to death!
I never planned to kill your child!
It was your frailness
that caused your miscarriage
after kneeling for only an hour.
You are the reason you couldn't keep your child.
How can you blame that on me?
I did resent you being favored
exclusively by His Majesty.
I’ve never seen His Majesty favor a woman so much.
With you in the palace,
His Majesty no longer cared for me.
I didn’t want to go back to waiting for him all night.
Any woman daring to vie with me for favor
must die.
True, I instructed Yu to kill you with poisons.
But I never thought of killing your child!
You didn't?
Although it was not your intent,
were it not for Pleasancy in your palace,
I would not have become so weak
and miscarry after kneeling for only one hour.
Pleasancy …
Pleasancy?
Do you know why you never conceived
another child after your miscarriage?
Do you know that Pleasancy contains
a large amount of musk?
You’ve been using it for so many years.
Of course you could never conceive a child.
Utter nonsense!
The incense was granted by His Majesty!
His Majesty…
Impossible.
It's impossible.
If it were not for His Majesty’s order,
Impossible ...
why didn’t any imperial doctor tell you
about the musk in your body.
Not only did he make you barren all these years,
the tonic that caused your miscarriage
was also by His Majesty’s order.
The prenatal tonic that Consort Honnête brought
only served to take the blame away from His Majesty.
No matter how much safflower you
forced Consort Honnête to drink,
it would never bring back your child.
Why?
Because you’re the daughter of the Nian family.
His Majesty had long been
vigilant against Nian Gengyao.
He’d never allow the birth of a child
bearing the blood of the Nians.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty!
What torment you inflicted on Shilan!
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Is Nian Shilan's funeral over?
She died in tragic despair.
His Majesty was silent for
quite some time when he heard of it.
His Majesty granted her a dignified burial,
with the protocol of Noble Consort and the
posthumous name Dunsu [gentle and solemn].
Although the protocol is intended for Noble Consort,
it's almost the end of the year，
so the funeral was arranged hastily.
Dun means gentle.
But was she ever gentle?
This posthumous name sounds ironic.
Whether it is irony or praise,
even though she was a Companion
at the end of her life,
after all, His Majesty
saved her face posthumously.
Not an honor she enjoyed when alive,
but a grace shown to the living.
His Majesty did this
because he doesn't want any talk of his meanness.
Just protecting his own prestige.
Honnête, you are clear-sighted.
How couldn't I be?
Only you and Lady Délice are in favor presently.
Having exclusive enjoyment of grace.
What is good about having a moment of grace?
It's terrifying to
lose one's clarity of mind for the favor of His Majesty,
like Nian Shilan.
You seem to have a lot of feelings for her today.
I thought I hated her in the extreme.
But now she's dead, I only feel miserable.
When she was married and favored,
how could she expect that after years of dominance,
the one she shared her pillow with
would plot against her.
To end up like this today.
Isn't that the life in the palace?
Plotting our glory and grace, as well as rank and title.
If we concubines can calculate them,
why can't His Majesty?
Can't we live without being calculating?
Yesterday morning,
I found the wrinkles around my eyes much deeper.
It reminded me of my age.
I have calculated
half of my life away.
Your Highness,
Concubine Aide has died.
Go get my things ready.
I'll be there shortly.
Go.
A few days ago, I noticed
Concubine Aide was feeling unwell.
How did she suddenly pass away?
Dr. Wen told me in confidence that
His Majesty and the Empress Dowager can't abide her.
So her servants were asked to poison her medicine,
and it caused nightmares after taking it.
Nian Shilan was deposed due to her accusation.
Now that Nian Shilan died,
the nightmares make it seem
she perished because of guilt.
Her Majesty warned the Imperial Infirmary beforehand
to stay uninvolved.
So they feigned ignorance.
Cao Qinmo was quite scheming.
Nevertheless,
she was no match for His Majesty and Her Majesty.
Concubine Aide betrayed Consort Fleur for her own gain.
Perhaps she would have been unfaithful to others.
I just pity Princess Wenyi.
Losing her mother so young.
I was thinking that
if Your Highness were willing to foster the princess,
she would be well educated in the future.
I believe His Majesty will not be opposed.
I do adore Princess Wenyi.
But such a decision
is not within our ability.
Since Your Highness favors the princess,
you certainly will regard her as your own daughter.
I will do my best to help Your Highness.
If this really happens,
I will promise her all that I have.
My Lady, I have placed ointment on your wound.
But looking at the wound,
it's somewhat improved but still not stable.
Please forgive me for my poor medical skills.
Don't blame yourself.
It's all due to my fragile health.
I hope it will not trouble you to visit a few more times.
This is no trouble at all, My Lady.
I will return tomorrow.
I have asked your servants to brew the prescribed herbs.
Please take it on time.
Allow me to take my leave, My Lady.
Take care, Dr. Wen.
My Lady, here's the medicine that
Dr. Wen prescribed today.
The medicine is so bitter.
Get some candied fruit for me.
Yes.
What's the matter?
Why is the wound still not better?
Fortunately, it's winter.
It would fester if the weather was hot.
You're already on a strict diet.
No fish or shrimp whatsoever.
but ...
My health has always been fragile.
I'm sure I'll recover after several more doses of medicine.
Don't worry.
It's late now. Let's go to bed.
Recently I have often felt fatigued,
without any reason.
You should also sleep, Meizhuang.
All right.
The "Western Expedition Essays"
were found during the confiscation
of Nian Gengyao's property.
Since it's not a precious item,
it was not brought to our attention until now.
It is full of audacious words of rebellion
against Your Majesty.
I brought it in immediately
for Your Majesty's disposition.
Flattery of Nian Gengyao
is found everywhere in this book.
It even commends Nian Gengyao as
the first giant in the universe.
Since I granted him suicide,
does it mean I killed the greatest man under heaven?
It's far more than that, Your Majesty.
It includes a discussion of era names,
saying Your Majesty's regnal name,
"Yong Zheng" is ominous
as historical emperors who took the name Zheng
usually had a miserable end.
It suggests that meritorious officials like
Nian Gengyao have been mistreated
because their monarch is mediocre and jealous of their talents.
And thus Your Majesty would eliminate him.
Nonsense!
May Your Majesty's anger be calmed.
Who wrote this treacherous book?
It's written by Niang Gengyao's advisor, Wang Jingqi.
How brazen and ridiculous!
If the people were to obtain this book,
then my reputation in history
would be ruined by such petty men.
May peace be restored in Your Majesty.
Announce my decree:
Wang Jingqi will be beheaded in public.
Hang his head in front of the market
for ten years
as a warning to all.
Women of the Wang family will become
slaves of the frontiersmen who surrendered.
And the men will be banished to Ningguta.
Any officials related to the Wang family
will be dismissed from their positions.
I can't allow someone like him to
perpetuate a poisonous legacy.
Yes, Your Majesty.
His Majesty's rage had me sweating.
Wang Jingqi was reliant on Nian Gengyao
and wrote such rebellious words.
It's natural His Majesty doesn't tolerate him.
However,
although Wang Jingqi was rightfully convicted
and he ought to die a thousand deaths,
hanging his head in the market for ten years ...
I can't imagine ...
how many citizens will feel their hearts tremble.
Mr. Zhen, do you not agree with
His Majesty's punishments?
Please don't joke of this, Mr. Emin.
How can I not agree with His Majesty's wise decision?
But Nian Gengyao is already dead
and with His Majesty's continued severe
punishment of those from his faction,
the court has been filled with an air of uneasiness.
But we both contributed to this
by condemning him, didn't we?
Of course.
Condemning those who have committed
crimes is our duty as civil officials.
But the entire Wang family being implicated ...
It's truly pitiful.
I've heard there are new paintings
and books on Chessboard Street.
Are you going to go take a look?
I was just planning on going there.
Would you like to come along?
When I left today, my wife asked me to come back early.
Let me know if you see anything worthy.
Of course.
Peace to Concubine Sourire.
Peace to Lady Vertu.
Your Highness, His Majesty bids you to arrive at
the Hall of Mental Cultivation at the usual time.
Understood.
Let's stop for today and we'll continue tomorrow.
Go and get tidied up so you don't
make His Majesty wait for you.
I shall.
Lunar, why hasn't Dr. Wen come to take my pulse yet?
Quick, go take a look.
Dr. Wen usually comes before dinner.
It's still early now.
Seems like I have remembered the time incorrectly.
Officials have reported that
Yun-e, in prison, has repeatedly
called me a small man
who held his wife and son hostage.
“The winner is enthroned; The losers outlawed.”
Yun-e used to be a state prince.
Now that he is a prisoner, it's not
surprising that his words are spiteful.
What is Your Majesty planning to do?
After all, Your Majesty's actions are just
as Yun-e was a rebel.
There is no pity even if he's killed.
Is Your Majesty angry just because
of Yun-e's accusations?
Huan Huan,
I care more about what my people think of me.
Then I ask Your Majesty
to grant a nominal noble title to Yun-e's son, Hongxuan.
Yun-e has accused Your Majesty of
holding his wife and son as hostage.
But if Your Majesty treats them generously,
and they have something to rely on,
then it will erase any doubt against Your Majesty.
Hongxuan is still young.
But it's exactly his young age that I favor.
Grind the ink for me.
I will write an edict to grant Hongxuan a noble title.
Your Majesty.
The last mourning ceremony for Noble Consort
Dunsu is being held at Baohua Hall.
I see. I will be there soon.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, allow me to take my leave.
Today marks the 7th week since Consort Fleur's death.
My Lady, she's already dead.
Why do you bring her up?
Ever since I witnessed Nian Shilan's death,
I have been feeling disturbed somehow.
Sometimes when I'm speaking to His Majesty,
I see her face suddenly appear in front of me.
I don't know if I will end up like her.
Nian failed because she did not have a son.
But if you were to have a child, My Lady,
your status would be stable.
If only it was as easy as wishing.
Even though I've been using the
medicine prescribed by Dr. Wen,
there still hasn't been any good news.
Why don't we
find and try some folk remedies?
Maybe they will be more effective
than the imperial prescriptions.
I wonder if you will speak such
nonsense again once you get married.
My Lady, I was just trying to think of ideas for you.
Even if my ideas aren't good,
why do you have to tease me?
I'm not teasing you.
In less than a year or so,
you won't be serving by my side anymore.
You can't be thinking of staying with me forever?
My Lady,
I'm speaking from my heart,
I don't want to be married off.
I only want to stay by your side forever.
Everything here is good
but everything here is also not.
If you had to stay here alone,
it would be too difficult for you.
You're speaking real nonsense now.
If you become an old maid,
then you won't be able to get married.
Jade, it is my turn to take night watch today.
Vermillion is waiting outside for you to go back with her.
Lady Meizhuang is already resting.
Go to bed early, My Lady.
I will go now.
Today, at the Hall of Mental Cultivation，
why did you ask to grant a title to State Prince Dun's son?
When I miscarried and then lost favor,
no one visited me,
except for Meizhuang and Consort Estime.
And, though neither relative nor friend, the
wife of State Prince Dun paid me a visit.
My Lady, you have a kind heart.
You are repaying a small kindness.
Although State Prince Dun is arrogant and domineering,
he is willing to sacrifice his life
to protect his wife and children.
Although he committed several offenses,
he is a good husband.
Peace and grace to Your Majesties.
You may rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Sourire, you are late.
Your penalty is cracking the walnuts
without eating them.
It's cold outside so I brought a hand-warmer.
But it unexpectedly cooled when I was halfway here.
I went back for a new one and made myself late.
Your hands are cold indeed.
Warm them up before you eat.
I thank Your Majesty.
If you eat cold food,
your stomach will suffer.
I thank Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
the concubine positions are largely empty.
Does Your Majesty have the intention of filling them?
Go on.
According to the imperial protocol,
there should be one Imperial Noble Consort,
two Noble Consorts,
four Consorts, six Concubines,
and the rest can be any number.
In the Consort ranks, there are only
Consort Estime, Consort Honnête and Consort Astuce.
The Concubine rank has Concubine Sourire only.
All are lacking.
There's no rush to fill the ranks of
Imperial Noble Consort and Noble Consort.
But there's one Consort we can add.
You can choose a good date
to promote Concubine Sourire to Consort.
I am still inexperienced in the palace.
This is not about experience.
Concubine Sourire exhibits outstanding virtue
and deserves to be promoted to Consort.
But Concubine Sourire has not served long
in the palace or borne any children.
When she conceives a child,
it will be a great honor to promote her to Consort.
No matter.
Promote her to Consort Sourire.
The second day of February is a good date.
I thank Your Majesties for the heavenly grace.
You may rise.
Congratulations, Sourire. This is such great news.
You are quick to congratulate Concubine Sourire.
How do you know you don't have
good news coming too?
Promote Noble Lady An to Concubine An.
Choose a good date for both promotions.
So it can be a joyous occasion for both of them.
Besides, Attendant Joie has served me for a long time.
Promote Attendant Joie to Noble Lady.
I thank Your Majesties.
I am deeply grateful.
Thank you, Sourire.
Congratulations, Lingrong.
You may rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
It's still early. I will go review some memorandums.
Concubine Sourire will come along with me
to help with grinding the ink.
Yes.
His Majesty departs.
- I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
- Allow me to take my leave.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.